[Music]
given the 60% surge in the adrenal
hormone neur adrenaline within minutes
of just drinking two cups of plain water
uh might one get the weight loss
benefits of Nord adrenalin releasing
drugs like a fedra without the risks you
don't know until you put it to the test
published in the Journal of the
endocrine Society the results were
described as uniquely
spectacular drinking two cups of water
increased the metabolic rate of men and
women by 30% the increase started within
10 minutes and reached a maximum within
an hour and then 90 minutes after
drinking a single tall glass of water in
the study subjects burned about an extra
25 calories do that four times a day
throughout the day and you could wipe
out 100 extra calories more than a fedra
you trim off more calories drinking
water than taking weight loss doses of
the Bann substance epidrin the active
component of edra three times a day and
we're just talking about plain cheap
safe and legal tap water using the 10
calorie rule I explained previously
unless we somehow compensated by eating
more or moving less drinking that much
water could make us lose 10 pounds over
time in essence concluded one research
team drinking water provides negative
calories a similar effect was found in
overweight and obese children drinking
about 2 cups of water led to a 25%
increase in metabolic rate within 24
minutes lasting at least 66 minutes
until the experiment ended so just
getting the recommended daily adequate
intake of water about seven cups a day
for children ages 4 through eight and
for ages 9 through 13 eight cups a day
for girls and 10 cups for boys may offer
more than just hydration benefits uh not
all research team were able to replicate
these findings though others only found
about a 10 to 20% increase 5% increase
or effectively none at all pouring cold
water one might say on the whole concept
what we care about though is weight loss
the proof is in the pudding let's test
the waters shall we some researchers
suggest the increase in metabolic rate
with water drinking could be
systematically applied in the prevention
of weight gain talk about a safe simple
side effect Free Solution in fact free
in every sense drug companies may spend
billions getting a new drug to Market
surely a little could be spared to test
something that in the very least
couldn't hurt that's the problem though
water is a costree
intervention there are observational
studies suggesting that those who drink
for example four more cups of water a
day appear to lose more weight
independent of confounding factors such
as less soda or more exercise but you
don't really know until you put it to
the test and finally in 2013 effective
water induced thermogenesis on body
weight body mass index and body
composition of overweight subjects 50
overweight girls actually women ages 18
through 23 were asked to drink two cups
of water three times a day half an hour
before meals over and above their
regular water intake without otherwise
changing their diets or physical
activity and they lost an average of
three pounds in 8 weeks what happened to
those in the control group there was no
control group a fatal flaw for any
weight loss study due to the Hawthorne
effect where just knowing you're being
washed and weighed May subtly affect
people's behavior of course we're just
talking about water so with no downsides
one might as well give it a try but i'
feel more confident if there were some
randomized control trials to really put
it to the test thankfully there are I
hate it when the title ruins the
suspense overweight and obese men and
women randomized to two cups of water
before each meal lost nearly 5 pounds
more body fat in 12 weeks than those in
the control group both groups were put
on the same calorie restricted di but
the one with the added water lost weight
44%
faster a similar randomized control
trial found that about one in four in
the water group lost more than 5% of
their body weight compared to only one
in 20 in the control group the average
weight loss difference was only about
three pounds but those who claim to have
actually complied with the three times a
day instructions lost about eight more
pounds compared to those who only did
the extra water once a day or less this
is comparable to commercial weight loss
programs like Weight Watchers and all
they did was drink some extra
[Music]
water for